<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.doubao.Murmur</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Doubao Murmur</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_CN">豆包语音输入</name>
  <summary>Voice-to-text input using Doubao ASR</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">使用豆包语音识别的语音输入工具</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Doubao Murmur is a voice-to-text input tool that uses Doubao's ASR
      (Automatic Speech Recognition) service to convert speech to text in
      real-time. It works as a global overlay with a push-to-talk button,
      making it easy to dictate text into any application.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">
      豆包语音输入是一款语音转文字工具，使用豆包的 ASR（自动语音识别）服务
      实时将语音转换为文字。它以全局悬浮窗的形式工作，提供一键录音按钮，
      可以轻松地将文字输入到任何应用中。
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.doubao.Murmur.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/lilong7676/doubao-murmur</url>
  <developer_name>lilong7676</developer_name>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.4.4" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>On-screen keyboard one-handed mode: widen from 22% to 35% of the
           screen so keys are large enough to tap (~6mm instead of ~4mm), and
           fix a keyboard reopened directly in a one-handed/split mode keeping
           a stale saved width and missing its compact styling. Width is now
           always derived from the current mode and monitor.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.3" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Recording overlay: wrap transcription text properly. Chinese has no
           spaces, so the default word-wrap found no break points and the text
           overflowed into a head-truncating ellipsis pinned at two lines. The
           overlay now wraps between characters and grows in height up to five
           lines before the oldest words scroll off.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.2" date="2026-06-11">
      <description>
        <p>Change the on-screen keyboard's global hotkey to Ctrl+Super+Shift
           (pure modifiers). The old Alt+Shift+F10+F11 chord leaked F-key
           escape sequences into focused terminals; modifier-only keys emit
           no characters, so nothing leaks.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.1" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>On-screen keyboard: make key presses reliable on the touchscreen
           (fire on the native button click, drop the gesture/poll path that
           dropped touch-release events and could deadlock the keyboard)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.0" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Add an on-screen touch keyboard: full/split/one-handed layout
           modes, sticky modifiers, symbols layer, drag &amp; resize, tray
           toggle, and the Alt+Shift+F10+F11 global hotkey</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.1" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Add system tray icon (StatusNotifierItem) with status menu</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.0" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Initial Linux/SteamOS release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
